rasmussenreports.com 2008-06-22

# Rasmussen Reports™: The most comprehensive public opinion coverage ever provided for a presidential election.

Rasmussen Reports is committed to protecting your privacy and a safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Rasmussen Reports Web site and governs data collection and usage. Rasmussen Reports will only share your information with outside parties in ways that are described in this privacy statement or if we are required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law, cooperate with law enforcement agencies, or comply with a legal process served on our web site. By using the Rasmussen Reports website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. 

**Collection of your Personal Information**

For registered members, Rasmussen Reports collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. For non-registered visitors, Rasmussen Reports also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites. 

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is logged by Rasmussen Reports. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by Rasmussen Reports for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Rasmussen Reports Web site. 

Rasmussen Reports encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites Rasmussen Reports may link to so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. Rasmussen Reports is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the Rasmussen Reports Web site. 

**Use of your Personal Information**

Rasmussen Reports collects and uses your personal information to operate the Rasmussen Reports Web site and deliver the services you have requested. Rasmussen Reports may use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Rasmussen Reports and its affiliates. Rasmussen Reports may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. 

Rasmussen Reports does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Rasmussen Reports may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Rasmussen Reports may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail and provide customer support. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Rasmussen Reports, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

Rasmussen Reports does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent. 

Rasmussen Reports keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within Rasmussen Reports, in order to determine what Rasmussen Reports services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Rasmussen Reports to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

Rasmussen Reports Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Rasmussen Reports or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Rasmussen Reports; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Rasmussen Reports, or the public. 

**Use of Cookies**

The Rasmussen Reports Web site use "cookies" to help you manage your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Rasmussen Reports services or Web sites you visit. 

**Security of your Personal Information**

Rasmussen Reports secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Rasmussen Reports secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

**Changes to this Statement**

Rasmussen Reports will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Rasmussen Reports encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Rasmussen Reports is protecting your information. 

**Contact Information**

Rasmussen Reports welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Rasmussen Reports has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Rasmussen Reports at [privacy@RasmussenReports.com](mailto:privacy@RasmussenReports.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
